A few years ago,
I broke into my own house.
I had just driven home,
it was around midnight
in the dead of Montreal winter,
I had been visiting my friend,
Jeff, across town,
and the thermometer on the front porch
read minus 40 degrees --
and don't bother asking
if that's Celsius or Fahrenheit,
minus 40 is where the two scales meet --
it was very cold.
And as I stood on the front porch
fumbling in my pockets,
I found I didn't have my keys.
In fact, I could see them
through the window,
lying on the dining room table
where I had left them.
So I quickly ran around
and tried all the other doors and windows,
and they were locked tight.
I thought about calling a locksmith --
at least I had my cellphone,
but at midnight, it could take a while
for a locksmith to show up,
and it was cold.
I couldn't go back to my friend
Jeff's house for the night
because I had an early flight
to Europe the next morning,
and I needed to get
my passport and my suitcase.
So, desperate and freezing cold,
I found a large rock and I broke
through the basement window,
cleared out the shards of glass,
I crawled through,
I found a piece of cardboard
and taped it up over the opening,
figuring that in the morning,
on the way to the airport,
I could call my contractor
and ask him to fix it.
This was going to be expensive,
but probably no more expensive
than a middle-of-the-night locksmith,